export const reviewQuestions = [
	{
		question: `List the days of creation.`,
		answer: ``,
	},
	{
		question: `List the ten commandments.`,
		answer: ``,
	},
	{
		question: `List the armor of God.`,
		answer: ``,
	},
	{
		question: `List the fruit of the Spirit.`,
		answer: ``,
	},
	{
		question: `List the books of the Old Testament.`,
		answer: ``,
	},
	{
		question: `List the books of the New Testament.`,
		answer: ``,
	},
];

export const generalQuestions = [
	/* From trivia time */
	{
		question: `Who were the first man and woman?`,
		answer: `Adam and Eve`,
	},
	{
		question: `What was the name of the good tree in the Garden of Eden?`,
		answer: `The tree of life`,
	},
	{
		question: `What was the name of the bad tree in the Garden of Eden?`,
		answer: `The tree of the knowledge of good and evil`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did Adam and Eve do wrong?`,
		answer: `Ate the fruit God said not to eat`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did God do to keep Adam and Eve out of the garden?`,
		answer: `Placed an angel with a fiery sword at the entrance`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who were Adam and Eve's first two sons?`,
		answer: `Cain and Abel`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did Cain do to Abel?`,
		answer: `Killed him`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did Noah build?`,
		answer: `The Ark`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who were Noah's sons?`,
		answer: `Shem, Ham, and Japheth`,
	},
	{
		question: `How many of each kind of animal went on the ark?`,
		answer: `Seven of each clean animal, two of each unclean animal`,
	},
	{
		question: `How did Noah know there was dry land again?`,
		answer: `He sent out a raven once and a dove three times`,
	},
	{
		question: `What is the sign of God's promise that He wouldn't flood the whole earth again?`,
		answer: `Rainbows`,
	},
	{
		question: `How did baby Moses' mommy save him?`,
		answer: `Floated him in a basket down the river`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did God tell Moses to say to Pharoh?`,
		answer: `Let my people go that they may worship me`,
	},
	{
		question: `Through what did God speak to Moses?`,
		answer: `Burning bush`,
	},
	{
		question: `What were some of the plauges of Egypt?`,
		answer: `Water into blood, frogs, lice, flies, sick livestock, boils, hail and fire, locusts, darkness, death of firstborn`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did the Israelites follow out of Egypt?`,
		answer: `A pillar of cloud by day and fire by night`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did God tell Moses to do to part the Red Sea?`,
		answer: `Raise his staff`,
	},
	{
		question: `Why did Balaam's donkey leave the road?`,
		answer: `There was an angel in the way`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did Balaam's donkey do when Balaam hit it?`,
		answer: `It asked, "Why are you hitting me?"`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who was the really strong man?`,
		answer: `Samson`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did Delila do to Samson?`,
		answer: `Cut his hair`,
	},
	{
		question: `What happened to Samson after his hair was cut?`,
		answer: `He wasn't strong anymore`,
	},
	{
		question: `What funny thing did Samson use to kill a thousand men?`,
		answer: `A donkey's jawbone`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did they do to Samson after they put him in jail?`,
		answer: `Blinded him`,
	},
	{
		question: `What was David's job as a boy?`,
		answer: `Shepherd`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did David kill with his slingshot before he met Goliath?`,
		answer: `A bear and a lion`,
	},
	{
		question: `How many stones did David take with him to face Goliath?`,
		answer: `5`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who was David's best friend?`,
		answer: `Jonathan`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who was Jonathan's dad?`,
		answer: `King Saul`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who was the first king of Israel?`,
		answer: `King Saul`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did David do to King Saul while he was sleeping?`,
		answer: `Took a corner of his robe`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who was King Solomon's dad?`,
		answer: `King David`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who was the prophet that made fun of the priests of Baal?`,
		answer: `Elijah`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did Elijah say they should do to see who is the real god?`,
		answer: `Call for fire from heaven`,
	},
	{
		question: `When God sent fire to burn up Elijah's offering, what else did it do?`,
		answer: `Licked up the water`,
	},
	{
		question: `How did Elijah go up into heaven?`,
		answer: `In a whirlwind`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did Elisha see when Elijah went up into heaven?`,
		answer: `Chariots of fire`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who was thrown into the fiery furnace?`,
		answer: `Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who else was in the fiery furnace?`,
		answer: `An angel`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who was thrown into the lions den?`,
		answer: `Daniel`,
	},
	{
		question: `What did the lions do when Daniel was in the den?`,
		answer: `They didn't eat him`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who was Jesus' mommy?`,
		answer: `Mary`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who was Mary's husband?`,
		answer: `Joseph`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who told Mary she was going to have a baby?`,
		answer: `The angel Gabriel`,
	},
	{
		question: `What gifts did the wise men bring for Jesus?`,
		answer: `Gold, frankincense, and myrrh`,
	},
	{
		question: `What was Jesus' first miracle?`,
		answer: `Turned water into wine`,
	},
	{
		question: 'With what did Jesus feed 5,000 people?',
		answer: 'Five loaves of bread and two small fish',
	},
	{
		question: `How did Jesus calm the storm at sea?`,
		answer: `He said, "Peace, be still"`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who betrayed Jesus?`,
		answer: `Judas Iscariot`,
	},
	{
		question: `Who denied Jesus?`,
		answer: `Peter`,
	},
	{
		question: `How did Jesus die?`,
		answer: `Nailed to a cross`,
	},

	/* https://icebreakerideas.com/bible-trivia-questions-answers/ */
	{
		question: 'In what city was Jesus born?',
		answer: 'Bethlehem',
	},
	{
		question: 'How many books are in the New Testament?',
		answer: '27',
	},
	{
		question: 'What type of insect did John the Baptist eat in the desert?',
		answer: 'Locusts',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who were the first apostles called to follow Jesus?',
		answer: 'Peter and Andrew',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Who recognized Jesus as the Messiah when he was presented at the Temple as a baby?',
		answer: 'Simeon',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who asked Pilate for Jesus’ body after the crucifixion?',
		answer: 'Joseph of Arimathea',
	},
	{
		question: 'Paul was shipwrecked on what island?',
		answer: 'Malta',
	},
	{
		question: 'Matthew was a _________.',
		answer: 'Tax collector',
	},
	{
		question:
			'To what city was Saul traveling when he encountered a great and blinding light?',
		answer: 'Damascus',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Who was the first person to come upon the injured man in the parable of the Good Samaritan?',
		answer: 'Priest',
	},
	{
		question: 'According to the Beatitudes who will be filled?',
		answer: 'Those who hunger and thirst for righteousness',
	},
	{
		question:
			'What does Simon Peter do for a living before he becomes an apostle?',
		answer: 'He was a fisherman.',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who is Stephen?',
		answer: 'The first Christian martyr',
	},
	{
		question: 'What was Paul’s name before he began preaching the gospel?',
		answer: 'Saul',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who is the high priest of Jerusalem who put Jesus on trial?',
		answer: 'Caiaphas',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Who doubted Jesus’s resurrection until he saw Jesus with his own eyes?',
		answer: 'Thomas',
	},
	{
		question:
			'For whom does Mary Magdalene mistake Jesus in his first resurrection appearance?',
		answer: 'The gardener',
	},
	{
		question: 'How did Judas identify Jesus to the Roman officials?',
		answer: 'He kisses him.',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who murders John the Baptist?',
		answer: 'Herod Antipas',
	},
	{
		question: 'What do we remember on Palm Sunday?',
		answer: 'Jesus’s entry into Jerusalem before his death',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who baptizes Jesus?',
		answer: 'John the Baptist',
	},
	{
		question: 'Which Gospel is written by a doctor?',
		answer: 'Luke',
	},
	{
		question: 'Where was Jesus born?',
		answer: 'Bethlehem',
	},
	{
		question: 'How many apostles did Jesus have?',
		answer: '12',
	},
	{
		question: 'What is the name of the disciple who betrayed Jesus?',
		answer: 'Judas Iscariot',
	},
	{
		question: 'How did Jesus die?',
		answer: 'He was crucified.',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who gave Jesus gifts when he was born?',
		answer: 'The wise men',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Who are the religious leaders who continually tried to trap Jesus with their questions?',
		answer: 'Pharisees',
	},
	{
		question: 'What is the name of Jesus’ mother?',
		answer: 'Mary',
	},
	{
		question: 'What did Jesus do for Lazarus?',
		answer: 'Raised him from the dead',
	},
	{
		question: 'What job did Jesus’ earthly father, Joseph, do?',
		answer: 'Carpenter',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Who wrote many of the letters to churches in the New Testament?',
		answer: 'Paul',
	},
	{
		question: 'Jesus told what kind of stories?',
		answer: 'Parables',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who wanted to kill Jesus when he was a baby?',
		answer: 'Herod',
	},
	{
		question: 'What did Simon Peter do for a living?',
		answer: 'He was a fisherman.',
	},
	{
		question: 'What happened to Jesus after the resurrection?',
		answer: 'He ascended into heaven.',
	},
	{
		question:
			'What did the Holy Spirit look like when the disciples received it?',
		answer: 'Tongues of fire',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who went on missionary journeys to preach to the Gentiles?',
		answer: 'Paul',
	},
	{
		question: 'How did Paul escape from Damascus?',
		answer: 'In a basket down the city wall',
	},
	{
		question: 'What is the last book of the New Testament?',
		answer: 'Revelation',
	},
	{
		question: 'What was the name of Adam’s third son?',
		answer: 'Seth',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who was the mother of Samuel?',
		answer: 'Hannah',
	},
	{
		question:
			'What kind of bird brought Elijah food while he hid in the Kerith Ravine, east of Jordan?',
		answer: 'Ravens',
	},
	{
		question: 'How many books are there in the Old Testament?',
		answer: '39',
	},
	{
		question: 'In what language is the Old Testament written?',
		answer: 'Hebrew',
	},
	{
		question: 'In what languages is the New Testament written?',
		answer: 'Greek and Aramaic',
	},
	{
		question:
			'From which country did Moses help the Israelites escape from their lives of slavery?',
		answer: 'Egypt',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Which tribe of Israel looked after the religious aspects of life?',
		answer: 'Levi',
	},
	{
		question:
			'On which day of the year could the High Priest enter the Holy of Holies in the Temple?',
		answer: 'Day of Atonement',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Israel split into two kingdoms after the reign of King Solomon, with Israel in the north, but what was the name of the southern kingdom?',
		answer: 'Judah',
	},
	{
		question: 'One title of God is El Shaddai, which means what?',
		answer: 'Almighty God',
	},
	{
		question: 'What does Israel mean?',
		answer: 'Prevails with God',
	},
	{
		question: 'What time period does the Old Testament cover?',
		answer: 'The beginning of man to the time of the Messiah',
	},
	{
		question: 'From which part of Adam’s body did God create Eve?',
		answer: 'Rib',
	},
	{
		question: 'What was the name of Abraham’s nephew?',
		answer: 'Lot',
	},
	{
		question:
			'What did God ask Abraham to sacrifice to him on Mount Moriah?',
		answer: 'His only son',
	},
	{
		question:
			'When Joseph was in prison, whose dream did he correctly interpret to mean he would be restored to his job?',
		answer: 'Butler',
	},
	{
		question: 'In what was baby Moses hidden?',
		answer: 'An ark of bulrushes',
	},
	{
		question: 'On what mountain did Moses receive the law from God?',
		answer: 'Mount Sinai',
	},
	{
		question: 'What was the ‘tabernacle’ for?',
		answer: 'To worship God in',
	},
	{
		question:
			'How did Rahab let the invading Israelites identify her house?',
		answer: 'She tied a red cord in the window',
	},
	{
		question: 'What weapons did Gideon use to defeat the Midianites?',
		answer: 'Trumpets, pitchers, and lamps',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who did Samuel anoint as the first King of Israel?',
		answer: 'Saul',
	},
	{
		question: 'How did David defeat Goliath?',
		answer: 'He threw a stone from his sling',
	},
	{
		question: 'How did Uriah die?',
		answer:
			'David had him placed in the most dangerous spot in the battle.',
	},
	{
		question: 'What was Cain’s punishment for the murder of Abel?',
		answer: 'He was made a restless wanderer on the earth.',
	},
	{
		question: 'What did Joseph’s brothers do to Joseph?',
		answer: 'They sold him into slavery.',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who was Moses’ successor after his death?',
		answer: 'Joshua',
	},
	{
		question: 'What was the name of David’s father?',
		answer: 'Jesse',
	},
	{
		question: 'Which prophet secretly anointed David as king?',
		answer: 'Samuel',
	},
	{
		question: 'Why does Cain kill his brother Abel?',
		answer: 'Because God was pleased by Abel’s sacrifice and not Cain’s.',
	},
	{
		question:
			'How does Jacob steal his brother, Esau’s, inheritance rights?',
		answer: 'By tricking his father with the help of his mother',
	},
	{
		question: 'From which catastrophe does Joseph save Egypt?',
		answer: 'Famine',
	},
	{
		question: 'How does God first appear to Moses?',
		answer: 'As a burning bush',
	},
	{
		question:
			'What object did God give to Moses to perform signs and wonders?',
		answer: 'A wooden staff',
	},
	{
		question: 'How does God feed the Israelites in the desert?',
		answer: 'Mana',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Why does Moses break the stone tablets inscribed with God’s commandments at Mount Sinai?',
		answer: 'Because the people are worshipping a golden idol',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Why does God curse the Israelites to wander the desert for forty years before entering the Promised Land?',
		answer: 'Because they did not believe that God would fight for them',
	},
	{
		question:
			'What do Moses and Joshua forbid the Israelites to do in the Promised Land?',
		answer: 'Intermarry with the native inhabitants',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who is Elisha?',
		answer: 'Elijah’s apprentice and successor',
	},
	{
		question:
			'What do the deaths of King Ahab and his wife Jezebel have in common?',
		answer: 'Dogs eat their blood.',
	},
	{
		question: 'Which Jewish festival results from the events in Esther?',
		answer: 'Purim',
	},
	{
		question: 'What did King Solomon ask for from God?',
		answer: 'Wisdom',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Who wrote this line “The Lord is my Shepherd, I shall not want”?',
		answer: 'King David',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who married Abraham?',
		answer: 'Sarah',
	},
	{
		question: 'Looking for a wife for Isaac, Abraham’s servant found:',
		answer: 'Rebekah',
	},
	{
		question: 'Jacob agreed to work 7 years for the hand of:',
		answer: 'Rachel',
	},
	{
		question:
			'This woman promised the Lord that if He would bless her with a son, she would dedicate the boy to Him. She later bore Samuel.',
		answer: 'Hannah',
	},
	{
		question:
			'This woman remained with her mother-in-law, Naomi, after Naomi’s husband and sons died.',
		answer: 'Ruth',
	},
	{
		question: 'This woman married Moses.',
		answer: 'Zipporah',
	},
	{
		question:
			'This brave Israelite woman became queen of Persia and used her influence to protect her people, the Jews.',
		answer: 'Esther',
	},
	{
		question:
			'This woman was given to Jacob as a wife deceitfully before he could marry her younger sister.',
		answer: 'Leah',
	},
	{
		question:
			'This Egyptian woman was Sarah’s handmaiden, and bore Ishmael through Abraham.',
		answer: 'Hagar',
	},
	{
		question: 'This wicked queen wanted to kill the prophet Elijah.',
		answer: 'Jezebel',
	},
	{
		question:
			'This woman was turned into a pillar of salt because she looked back as Sodom and Gomorrah were being destroyed.',
		answer: 'Lot’s wife',
	},
	{
		question: 'What was the boat Noah built called?',
		answer: 'The ark',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who received the 10 commandments from God?',
		answer: 'Moses',
	},
	{
		question: 'What was the name of Moses’ brother?',
		answer: 'Aaron',
	},
	{
		question: 'What food do we ask God to give us in the Lord’s Prayer?',
		answer: 'Bread',
	},
	{
		question:
			'People look on the outward appearance, but what does God look on?',
		answer: 'The heart',
	},
	{
		question: 'His father gave him a coat of many colors.',
		answer: 'Joseph',
	},
	{
		question: 'This prophet was swallowed by a fish.',
		answer: 'Jonah',
	},
	{
		question: 'Who is the Son of God?',
		answer: 'Jesus',
	},
	{
		question: 'What was the name of Jesus’ mother?',
		answer: 'Mary',
	},
	{
		question: 'What did Jesus’ father do for a job?',
		answer: 'Carpenter',
	},
	{
		question: 'Jesus told a parable about a prodigal _____.',
		answer: 'Son',
	},
	{
		question: 'What is the shortest verse in the Bible?',
		answer: 'Jesus wept',
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the apostles betrayed Jesus?',
		answer: 'Judas',
	},
];
